Listen to all that rain.
All the thunder.
Skies break open.
I'm drinking coffee.
Today I'm feeling a little sluggish for some reason, but I'm still in a great mood.
I'm just feeling slow in my actions.
So I'm drinking a very nice and hot coffee and we're gonna relax to the max and play some games.
Oh, that's hot.
Oh, that's way too hot.
I need to wait a bit.
Damn it, I always do that.
It's like I'm surprised every time I drink from the coffee, you know?
Surprise, it's hot!
What's up, everybody?
Hey there, Oliver.
You always jump-scare me?
That should not be possible.
There's a cooldown.
Specifically, so I don't jump-scare you.
There's a lot of sun.
Kind of wish it was raining.
Dude, I love the rain.
I don't blame you.
Rain is awesome.
It does kind of remind me as well of the intros to Rainworld.
That was nice.
Hey there, Kreyfak.
Is that how I pronounce your name?
Kreyfak?
The Lord Eternal?
The Raven Warrior has arrived?
Mmm, a cup of joe.
Indeed.
I love that expression.
A cup of joe.
Who is joe?
And why is it named after him?
Loving the new series?
Are you talking about Prey?
Because if that's the case, then I agree.
I also love it.
It's amazing.
It rained like hell today and it was super cool.
Hey, that's it.
It's the best feeling ever when it's just pissing down outside.
And you're sitting inside just chilling.
What's up, Dr. Mother?
Why do you have a cake on your thing?
Hold on.
What does that mean?
r slash place 2023.
That's some Reddit stuff.
Aha!
You got some kind of symbol.
Cool.
What's up, Karaki?
Good evening, kind sir.
Good evening to you as well.
Oh, you're in Spain.
It's hot as hell, I can imagine.
How do you even sleep at night?
Well, depends whether or not it's a humid hot or a dry hot, right?
If it's humid, it's terrible.
That's why the summers in Denmark are so terrible when it's too hot.
It's too humid.
Ready to unearth the ancient secrets?
Dude, I'm so ready.
I really am.
And I have a great build going right now.
I'm in Barcelona.
Ah, cool.
Catalonia.
I watched two and a half episodes of Prey then decided to buy it.
I've seen a lot of comments like that.
That's so awesome.
Yeah, I also got the feeling that this game wasn't very well known.
Which is crazy to me, because so far at least, the game is amazing.
Like, it's super original.
It looks good.
It feels good.
It plays good.
It's just all-around great.
You're watching from Russia.
The heat here is really bad and it rarely rains.
Oh, that sucks.
I wish upon you a shower of rain, sir.
Time for more Pemera... Pemera Tonta Valtula.
Indeed.
I can't pronounce that.
I feel like I should be better at Finnish, since I was dating a Finnish girl once.
And she taught me a bunch of Finnish, but I forgot it all ever since.
Actually, I remember one word.
Yustukumina.
Which means it's some kind of spice and you add to food.
That's what I remember.
I have great memories of Finland.
I was out wandering the woods in the northern Finland, collecting mushrooms and putting them in sauce and making food with it.
That was awesome.
Yustukumina.
Exactly.
That's the one.
Something about cheese.
Yustu is cheese, right?
I love the Finnish titles.
Thanks.
They're kind of broken Finnish, though.
I'm not very good at... I mean, I use a mix of Google Translate and chat GPT to fact-check whether or not I'm right.
I'm like, is this what you would say as a Finnish gamer?
And chat GPT is like, definitely.
This is what all gamers say.
And then the first comment is like, you wouldn't say this at all.
I'm from Finland.
And I'm like, fuck!
I need someone to fact-check me a third time.
But yeah, I'm trying my best to make some cool titles.
Okay.
Guys, I'm too excited.
I need to play Noita.
I'm gonna jump in.
By the way, if you can hear some noise in the background, I turned on my dishwasher right before this, which in hindsight wasn't the greatest idea.
I didn't think things through, but things needed to get washed real bad.
So I turned it on.
Hopefully you can't hear it.
Otherwise, it's probably gonna get drowned out by all the spell casting we're gonna do today.
The last VOD translated to It Roams the Land?
God damn it.
Well, I guess I never gave the the wizard a name, right?
So for all intents and purposes, that wizard could be an It.
Who knows?
It roams the land.
Yep.
Okay, I'm gonna jump in.
You can't see me, of course.
There we go.
Now you should be able to see me.
So I'm just gonna take it a bit slower than usual.
At least I'm gonna try to, because I am a little slow today.
And I'm gonna just really calmly try and find some cool stuff in this game.
And roam the earth, as they say.
That is awesome.
Okay, let's see where we were.
Holy shit, I'm in a very scary spot.
Let me remind myself.
I have The Rock, Dwayne Johnson, and I have Digging Wand, and I have... Hold on, I need to fix the settings here.
There we go.
Now I can hear myself better.
Or at least hear the game, I mean.
So I think I had some trouble with this last time.
I remember changing this out.
I don't remember why.
But I was... I think there was an issue with the damage, but I couldn't quite figure out what the problem was.
I'm just gonna move on.
So I am now in the sewers, and basically what I'm trying to do is to find a better Digging Wand, so I can go back up.
Because I want to go back to the surface, now that I'm strong and powerful.
So that is the goal right now.
But if that means going deeper, then so be it, you know?
We can always go back up.
We just need that wand, or the spell.
I have 285 HP, which is a little over half.
That's good.
We have a Rockman.
I also have a Rockman.
Whoops, didn't mean to destroy that.
The sound is a little too low now.
There we go.
Good.
And I have 13k gold.
Because I have a gold perk.
So whatever comes my way, I'm gonna purchase it.
It's to the ambience.
Wait, is that a Rock in the distance I hear?
Sounds like one of my rocks having a little tantrum.
Slime.
Okay, let's just move on.
That is Berserkium.
That's actually great.
I want that.
Cover me in Berserkium.
Oh nice, so there's a portal there.
But I'm not done exploring here.
Not yet.
I've been here, I think, because of the Rock.
Another portal.
Whoops.
This Rock is insane, by the way.
This is actually... it feels like a broken build.
What is that thing?
Steel.
That explodes, right?
Oh,
he died from something.
They're blocking all my shots somehow.
Oh, and I'm immune to fire, which is awesome.
But it also means I'm constantly oily and slippery.
That's an issue.
My rock, my pet rock.
This is like a shower of sparks, basically.
That's what this wand is.
Especially great against small animals like this.
Oh shit!
Chaos!
Water me, water me?
Good.
Everything dies.
It's so cool that the game doesn't just break or like crash when you make a wand like this.
It seems completely insane, right?
You can do something like this.
Oh no, no, you're chasing the wrong one!
Come on, Rock.
Kill them all.
There was a lightning guy.
I think he died.
The Rock took care of him.
He was up here.
Emphasis on Woz.
Oh, and I also have this.
Watch.
Telekinesis.
Boink.
Kill that dude.
Oh my god, he didn't even die.
Wait, what's happening here?
Oh, nevermind.
So I need a plasma cutter, even though it's scary to have.
There's something up here, it seems.
What do we got?
Wha- ooh!
Hello?
What the fuck?
Yo, digging blast!
That's it, right?
What's this?
Manage to damage?
Didn't I already have one?
Whoops, I didn't mean to buy that.
Fuck!
I was gonna open my thingy here, and I clicked E instead of C.
God damn it.
What did I buy?
Did I buy a chain bolt?
Shit.
God damn it!
I want digging blast.
Oh, and watch this.
I can change my wands wherever I am.
Oh, he finally died down here.
Whoever that was.
Oh, and I'm immune to fire!
That's right!
I keep forgetting.
Well, it's probably a good thing that I don't get used to it, right?
It's a bad thing to get used to.
So if I do this now... Oh no.
Steel though?
Oh no, it still doesn't go through steel.
More powerful digging though.
What if I do both?
It's way slower.
I like that.
Definitely more powerful.
We can make our way through some stuff.
Like, we can't go through that, unfortunately.
That's steel.
Metal pipe is fine.
So like, this Oh, there's another one here.
How do I get in there?
Hey!
Can I find an opening?
Okay.
Can I actually get in there?
Oh wait, that's the beginning!
What the hell?
How did I miss this wand?
Oh, unless I didn't, and I already saw this one.
Maybe I'm dumb here.
Yeah, that one sucks.
Go back down here.
In fact, water it.
Makes it.
Sweet.
Oh, shit.
Can I get through here?
Yes, I can.
Oh, I have to remember I have the teleport bolt as well.
I can probably do some stuff with that to get through tight corridors, right?
Oh, I'm poisoned.
Ah!
There we go.
Shit, I really need to be able to dig, man.
This is a disaster.
I can't get anywhere.
That's just, that's rusted steel.
Can't get through that.
Hmm.
For all I know, that could be an insane wand with some sick digging stuff on it.
Should I buy this?
I'm buying it.
No, I'm not.
Not yet.
I'm saving.
I already have one of them.
There it is.
Feel that guy?
Pee on it.
Mix it.
Oh, wait.
I'm freezing it.
This is a freezing thing, isn't it?
A heart freezingly sinister aura.
Damage ice.
Yeah.
Oh, it's wanting to go up there.
What is that?
Looks like one of those enemies, but like inactive.
Nice, I made it.
Yo!
Black holes, but unfortunately they're not infinite.
Yeah, that's the issue here.
Shit.
What is the wand like?
Well, it's not that great.
Only three slots, right?
Okay.
If only that was infinite, huh?
How crazy would that be?
Let me get rid of that thing.
Blow it.
I made a bunch of ice.
Can I dig away the freezing vapor?
I'll just go through here.
Die.
Good.
150 HP.
If I go 100, I think it's time to move on and find some HP.
It's simply too dangerous.
Wow.
This rocks killed everything in here.
And that was a lot.
Feel that, dude.
Oh, someone shooting.
That's berserkium.
I took a little too much damage there.
What do we got here?
I can't get through.
I honestly don't know what I'm looking for here.
Well, the wand, I guess, but the digging.
The only digging I'm aware of that could help me here is actually the plasma.
Aha!
What do we have here?
Large fire bolt.
2,300 mana.
Dude.
That is a lot.
40 damage, 60 explodey.
But you know what?
We can do this.
Hold on.
Let me get rid of this one.
I'm scared.
See?
I keep wanting to press E to open my inventory.
If I now save this here, I can actually... Let's throw out of these.
Ah!
The wand is crazy, but I want to try something here.
What if I do this?
That is a lot of damage.
I think that's good.
Honestly, I'm not sure because I don't have the DPS thingy on.
Whoa.
Hold on.
Is this actually gonna kill me?
Is that damage to me?
Can that hurt me?
Oh, I don't know.
I guess we'll find out.
I kind of want to use this for a bit.
I can always hot swap it.
That's the crazy part.
I have the perk for it.
Whoa!
Shit!
I forgot I had... I forgot I just changed the wand.
I know it sounds insane, but I was immediately expecting when I press 4 to shoot the frost thingy, but that's fine.
Let's just run with this for a bit.
That's an enemy.
Does this dig by the way?
It does, but does it dig here?
It does not.
Okay.
Well, it's a sick digging wand, I guess, for soft materials.
Not bad at all.
Now that right there is scary.
Let's get rid of that.
Hey yo!
Okay, it's very powerful.
60 HP!
Uh-oh.
Yeah, we gotta go.
We gotta go.
I'm fucking done here.
It's over.
Also, I may have hurt myself a little bit.
I'm gonna put this back.
Just for safety reasons.
Safety comes first.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Oh, oh, wait, I need this back.
Almost forgot that.
Holy shit.
Okay.
I guess I could go back where I came from.
Yeah, I'm gonna do that.
I'm not gonna risk going down here.
Let me go this way.
Anything I want here, maybe I should buy this on the way out.
Nah, you know what?
I could come back, and that's probably gonna be insanely expensive spells when I go through Portal anyway, so let's save this money.
Did not come from there, unfortunately.
Be over here somewhere.
Diamonds.
Wait, what's going on here?
That's electrified.
Hold on.
What's going on there?
I'm intrigued.
All right.
I'm not intrigued enough.
We played safe.
Portal, portal, portal.
Oh, shit.
Where the fuck was it?
Down here?
Let me go more to the right.
No, no, I haven't been here.
What the hell?
Was it over here?
Oh.
Honestly, I'm not sure.
It doesn't look too promising, but let's just clear the area.
We can do it.
I don't like that this guy is attracting my rock.
It's annoying me.
Access granted.
Have fun.
What is that?
Wait, toxic ice?
I've never seen that.
Cool.
I hear.
I think.
Yeah, there we go.
There we go.
Honestly, let's just go.
Made it.
I'm taking this immediately.
No, no chances here.
Okay, let's see what we got.
Another digging bolt.
Explosive electric.
Oh, let's see perks.
Mournful spirit.
Dying creatures leave behind a spirit that deals damage.
No.
See, this is a bit unfortunate.
This should have been taken early on, right?
So it's not actually very good now.
Trick blood money.
No, I'm gonna re- I'm gonna, yeah, re-roll that shit.
Kills to mana.
Every time an enemy near you dies, you release mana recharging liquid.
Okay.
When near danger, you sprout fungal stuff?
More hatred.
I don't like this either.
I want to re-roll again.
Low recoil.
Recoil caused by your spells is greatly reduced, but your spells fly slightly slower.
Homunculus?
I've had that one before.
More love.
Creatures become more friendly too.
You know what?
I don't like this one.
I don't like that my spells fly slower.
And I- I actually kind of like recoil because that means I can fly around.
Ah, man, I don't have enough money to re-roll, so I'm gonna go with more love, I guess.
Maybe that's better for me.
If everything- if everyone calms the fuck down, you know, it can only be good for me.
Let's take that.
What's going on here?
Oh, I have so many perks.
I can't even show them all.
All right, well, I have no more money for these, which is fine.
I don't really want these anyway.
This one we can save.
I guess we just leave.
Dun, dun.
What is this?
Gamble?
Oh, I gambled for two random perks, that's right.
Oh, hello, hello, hello.
Oh, this guy.
Hold on, that's scary, that's scary.
Here's a rock fort.
Why is that blowing- blowing so blue up here?
Oh, I'm stuck, I'm stuck, I'm stuck!
Why is that so blue up here, but it's not blue down there?
Whoa!
Like, this is way more blue than usual.
Hey, you like jars?
At least I can kill him with that wand.
That's good.
Those were the guys I had issues with with my rock, because they were ghosts.
Boink!
So I guess we gotta farm a bunch of gold, find some digging stuff.
What is that?
Oh, it's that crystal.
I think the- remind me what the red ones do.
They crumble the earth, right.
Pretty neat, actually.
And I can't dig in any of this, unfortunately.
I need a more powerful digging.
What's up, dude?
They're trying to cast some stuff on me.
Wow, it doesn't actually attract to those guys over here.
The homing doesn't work on the traps.
That's a large bone.
Coming through.
What do I want to do?
Where do I want to go first?
I'm gonna do what I said a long time ago.
I'm gonna start at the top, because I keep going down for some reason.
This is where I entered.
Let me go left.
Straight left now.
Why does it say block on them?
I feel like that's something that's been happening, quite recently, in this run.
Enemies started to block my stuff.
And it wasn't an issue earlier on.
That is berserkium, I think.
Can't quite tell.
It's something.
Interesting.
Oh, wait a minute.
I need to be on the lookout here for these numbers.
Last time, we saw a four on a statue.
Look at the statue.
It's collapsed.
I actually kind of forgot what this area was called.
Was it the art?
I didn't pay attention when I entered.
Hey!
That's for you.
Oh, there's something up there.
Oh, it's the scorpion or what?
Jesus.
Calm down, rock.
Egg.
Okay, there's something there.
Yeah, yeah.
What the hell's going on up there?
Oh, shit.
That was a little Huerta helping me, I think.
He was charmed.
I'm not sure what the deal is with that.
Come on, rock.
Kill them all.
Yes!
It's so good.
It's the best.
Wow, that guy is completely blocked.
Oh, the rocks are fu- Oh, okay, I see.
Get him.
Keep going up.
Kind of want to break this one, just because it's so fun.
Oops.
Break it.
Everything collapses.
So cool.
If I could have infinite collapse, I like earthquake.
That would be fun.
Uh, that is the cursed shit, isn't it?
Don't want to deal with that.
But here- Oh, dude, here's what I could do to dig.
I can pick up a red crystal and take it with me.
I have telekinesis and then break it where I want to dig.
It's a little, uh, you know, not optimal, but it'll do the job.
No, wait, the green one is the curse, no?
That is the cursed shit.
I think the other one I saw up there is the one that releases a bunch of small purple explosions.
Whoa!
How did I get hit?
I can sort of bend the bullets, you know, around corners here.
It's great.
Let's go up.
What was in these?
Him is right.
Whoops.
Oh, that guy, I see him.
Get out of here.
Two crystals I definitely don't want to release or explode.
Although, give me that.
Let's, uh, throw that over there.
Is that gonna explode in the water?
On the lava?
Maybe not.
I wonder if I'm immune to lava, actually.
It says immune to fire, right?
But does that include lava?
It's hot, right?
It's just hotness.
Oh, that's a weird spell.
Go back, guy.
Blow up these.
This one is sick.
Oh, nice.
It's been a while.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Oh, a trap.
But that's fire, so I should be immune.
What is that?
Chaotic polymorphine?
Yeah, no.
How about that?
We don't want to do that.
That's a dead end.
Shit.
No, it's not.
Like, I was lying.
Duh!
What?
He teleported me.
Oh!
Oh, that's so confusing!
That is so confusing.
My perspective is totally fucked when he does that.
Can I kill this guy?
Still can't.
Wait, did I just...
Oh, I just froze all the lava!
No, wait, that's not true.
I put ice down here, which then got turned into steam, which then got turned into water, which then made this into rock, I think.
That's what actually happened.
Oh, shit.
Get away from me.
Keep thinking this is an enemy, but it's not.
Bye-bye.
Already at 8k money again.
It's crazy how fast I accumulate this.
This is basically a sand soccer.
This consumes sand.
A piece of the gut floats towards me.
Look at all that money.
I think I have the unstuck button, which is the digging wand.
That just did a lot of damage to me.
I don't want to get in there.
I just don't... I don't want to aggro him.
But how do I get...
Can I hit this?
I can't.
Shit.
But this is... I should be able to get through here.
And then maybe I can... Oh, wait, wait, we have a crystal.
Let's use this right there.
Collapse things.
Oh, it's like a weird... It works in a weird way.
It only collapses things above it somehow.
It's a bit odd.
Why am I going in here?
Don't go in there, actually.
Shit.
That's a dead end.
Going somewhere else.
Oh, no.
Hey, pupsy.
Kill him.
Kill that.
Kill everything.
Yank.
What is that below me?
Oh, there's a scorpion.
Open that.
What did I get?
A bunch of money, I think?
Sick.
16k.
We are rich.
Gunpowder and cursed meat?
What happens if I eat cursed meat?
Oh!
Cool?
All right.
So that's what happens.
You feel a dark presence looming or some sort.
I feel there's a very big lack of wants here.
Come on, man.
Give me some wants.
Oh, it does hurt him.
But in a weird way.
Oh, that's weird.
Stay there for all I care.
Let's go down then.
But if I go through this part, that's like the end boss, isn't it?
I don't want to do that.
This is not the goal of this expedition.
What was that?
Crystal.
I'm taking that.
Give me that.
What the hell is that down there?
Hold on.
I'm not sure.
I'm not sure what that is.
Oh, look at all the gold.
Wow.
Damn.
That's a lot.
Yep.
Taking care of.
Is that a Hamish thing?
Whoa.
Okay.
Oops.
I see.
There's a mage.
I'm scared of those.
You don't like the mages.
Whoa.
Take care of that one.
I thought it was a projectile for a second, but it was actually an enemy.
So watch this.
Turn to rock.
It's actually such a good utility.
Lava is no more.
And rock I can just dig through.
Oh, shit.
I can get through any amounts of lava, basically.
Isn't that awesome?
Oh, hello.
Get him.
That was 9,000 damage.
At least I think it was.
It was quite a lot.
Got him.
Like, this rock is significantly better than the one I had in the last run.
It's a lot easier to kill some of these enemies.
Can I really not go any further here?
I kind of wish I could just go on this doorway right here.
I'm gonna go down here, then.
Okay.
That looks promising.
We have a red crystal.
Kill that guy.
Look at the way he just pooped out an extra nugget there.
Like, it fell out.
Like, there's a significant lack of hearts and wands in this level.
What the hell's going on?
Whoa!
What just happened?
I got teleported.
That was weird.
All right.
There's a big jump scare there.
Fine.
Oh, get away from me.
Pee on it.
Let's go.
Go find an enemy.
Come on.
That's right.
This is how you do it, man.
What?
Wait a minute.
How did I just...
Did I step in something?
Is this...
What?
I don't understand how I just went over here.
I don't... I don't... I don't get it.
We have a chest.
Can I get in there?
Oh, there's a guy.
He's no more.
He died.
Uh, maybe if I go this way down here, could work.
Oh, definitely cannot work.
But hold on.
I have a red crystal.
I know exactly what to do.
Watch this.
It's gonna be so sick.
Uh, can I somehow launch this?
I'm gonna throw it up and shoot it.
Watch.
Break it apart.
Yes!
What?
I broke the chest.
Whoa!
Did I just, uh... What the hell just happened?
I don't know what was in that chest.
Maybe it's the... for the best that I don't find out.
This actually barely keeps me afloat.
I... Never mind.
It does not.
Hamis!
Hamis dead.
Okay.
Man, this level is no problem.
I'm owning it.
Don't shoot that shit at me.
27k money!
I don't even understand how I'm getting so much.
I mean, I get I have a perk and all, but...
Uh-oh.
Fuck you.
Bro, the the mages that, uh, have the randomized spells, they scare me.
Because I don't know what to expect.
I am scared, okay?
The fucked up thing is that the rocks actually follow the ghosts, but they can't penetrate them.
So they just sort of orbit around them.
Yo.
Number four again.
Uh, no rock.
That's the wrong way.
Hold on.
I have an idea.
I'm gonna launch it towards this guy.
Watch.
It doesn't work.
Okay, so there's something up there.
Very strong pull.
There we go.
Wells wants some.
It's doing something down there.
So cool.
Okay, so those guys were the scary ones in my last run.
But with this rock, no problem.
Actually, no problem.
I'll wait up in here, I think.
That guy is gonna annoy me.
There we go.
I have mined him out of existence.
Actually, he's still alive.
How dare you?
I told you to stay dead.
Feel both of those.
30k money.
That's nothing to scoff at.
Meanwhile, this rock is going nuts.
Stop going nuts, please.
Still up there.
That's unreal.
He died.
Come on, dude.
How are you not dead?
Oh, don't break that.
Don't break that.
Whoa.
Yeah, see, that's the purple explosion.
Wanna dance?
I don't think he's dead.
He's frozen.
This guy is still alive.
He's actually annoying me.
Come on, get out.
All right, fine, stay there.
That's curse.
We don't like the curse.
Oh, no, that's bad.
That's a really strong spell he makes there.
Oh, no, not this guy.
Why am I so... Oh, okay.
What do we have here?
Well,
just turn it all into a fucking rock.
It even goes through somehow.
Give me this.
Honestly, I don't know where I'm going.
I'm just hoping for a wand here.
A digging wand, please.
What's that?
Unstable... you know what?
That could be useful here.
Let me get rid of that shit.
Let me unstable teleportation myself.
Let's be ready to kill whatever happens... comes out.
Okay, here we go.
There we go.
We were ready.
All right.
Maybe I should do it near a wall.
Let me go as west as I can until I can't go west any here, for example.
Can I get over here?
That teleported me right into an arrow.
Watching this stuff.
Probably this is a bad idea with the whole teleportation.
But it seems like a good idea, doesn't it?
Like on the surface, it seems like a great idea.
Oh, no.
I haven't been here.
What's that?
Slime.
Oh, the red one.
Be careful on that.
Wand!
That's what I'm talking about.
There's more up here.
Who else wants a piece of me?
Reveal thyself?
What the hell's going on over here?
Oh, oh, that hurts.
Can I get in there?
I got to some new place.
Let's see where I am.
Oh, I'm right below.
Cool.
I guess I can open a permanent access here using this.
Shit, I missed.
Look at how weirdly this crystal wants to stay upright.
Shit.
Come on.
There we go.
Break it apart.
Uh oh.
Oh, oh, oh, falling debris hurts.
That's a new fear I have.
I didn't realize it hurt that much.
Shit.
Got him.
Huh.
Kill these guys.
There we go.
And that guy.
That guy over there.
That's one weird.
That's right.
A chest.
Uh oh.
Big guy coming.
Open the chest.
Fuck.
All right.
I'm going to lure him over here.
I'm going to go over there and open it.
But why is the stone homing on the chest?
That scares me.
Nice.
I guess I didn't need that, but sure.
Didn't realize that could be in a chest.
That's awesome.
I wonder what else can be in chests.
Oh, a wand.
Also, where's that wand I saw just before?
I remember that.
I saw a wand.
Oh, there it is.
Uh, let me unstable myself.
Just fucking shoot this.
This place is massive.
Ah, that's solid.
I saw that.
Nice.
Hey.
Fantastico.
A wand.
Increase lifetime.
That's awesome.
Increases the lifetime of a spell.
When could that be good?
Maybe with a black hole, actually.
How much longer are we talking?
Uh, I can actually store that.
Wait a minute.
Give me that.
Replace that.
We don't need that shit anymore.
Thank you.
Oh, nice, nice, nice.
So it only goes to a certain depth.
Look, I can't sort of go more than that.
So I have to keep digging.
But I am making it safe.
Insanity wand.
I am being rewarded here for my curiosity.
I'm finding things.
There's a wand, right?
What the hell is that?
It's a coup.
The hell?
Is that?
And I'm slippery as hell because I am oiled up.
Polymorphine?
How about no?
I want to get up there and get that wand.
I
think there was a hammers in there.
Wait, it's not an enemy.
Is it?
Hold on.
I kind of want to take you with me.
Let me get rid of that.
Can I pick you up?
Hey, that looks like a moon.
This tiny celestial object has a strong gravitational pull.
Oh, interesting.
I will bring that with me because that's new and exciting.
What is this?
Quadruple spell magic guard.
Holy lance?
A fast flying penetrating lance that glows with power.
Dude, I love the lances.
I have to try this.
Dormant crystal with trigger.
A crystal that explodes and casts another spell when caught in an explosion.
Okay, and a nuke.
Pinpoint of light.
Does this dig, I wonder?
An extremely concentrated point of light that explodes after a moment.
Interesting.
Let's see here.
What do I not want?
Maybe I don't want burst of air or that one.
I also do not want the... I do want the double.
Maybe the trifurcator can go away.
Small teleport bolt.
We don't need that because we already have one.
Now that we can edit our ones anywhere.
That's crazy, by the way.
Now I want to grab that one.
Let's try that.
I also want this.
I want that.
I don't want this.
Although... No, I don't want that.
This one I want to try and the nuke.
Obviously we're going to try.
Also this one, healing bolt.
If I can figure out how to make this heal me, that would be glory days, wouldn't it?
The large fire bolt.
I mean, I guess I could store some... Wait a minute.
Let me try this first.
Yo, pretty dope.
Oh, that's the spell the guy uses against me.
The floating hand or whatever.
The little ball of light.
That does how much damage?
Five and it explodes for 10, but only after a very long time.
I don't think that's super cool.
That one.
I almost killed myself.
Yup.
That's bad.
That's real bad.
Oh no.
That was close, dude.
Let's try this one.
Look at the recall on me.
Yo, wait, wait.
What's happening?
Oh, is that my digging wand?
Yo, wait.
Huh?
How did I make everything?
Oh wait, was it the crystal?
Did I destroy crystal?
That's probably what happened, isn't it?
Wait, damage explosive.
Explosive radius 30.
Damage holy 44.
Bro.
I don't know if this will damage me.
But the recall on this is wild.
Definitely want to hold on to that.
Maybe I don't use the nuke, huh?
Maybe I do not use that.
It's like a bad idea.
Reduce recharged.
How about we just put that here?
Because we don't know where else to put it.
And what else?
Increase lifetime?
What?
Maybe increase lifetime of...
Let's see here.
What would I like to increase the lifetime of?
Maybe the...
Dude, if I can find the circle of healing, I can increase the lifetime.
Imagine that.
See, that would be a use.
Let me try and figure this out.
There's got to be a way.
Let me get rid of that.
This one I like.
Healing bolts.
What can we put it on?
What if we put it on... No, this is a projectile in itself, right?
Watch.
If I shoot this, it shoots up.
So if I can somehow stand in its line, you know?
How can I do this?
Can I even... What if I stand next to a wall and shoot the wall?
So that I'm right on it.
Let's try that.
Let me just shoot down.
It does not heal me.
Fuck me.
Okay.
A magical bolt with rejuvenating... Rejuvenated power.
So damage healing minus nine.
Yeah.
So basically, I know this will work.
I just need to hit myself with it.
Dude, I think I know how to do it.
If we can get to a easy base, we just hit those reflective places and shoot the spell at ourselves.
That's how you can do it.
That would be cool.
So, but first I got to get up there, right?
For now though, kind of just want to have my old wand back.
No, no, not yet.
Save this up here.
Grab this.
There.
Okay.
Neat.
I think we're ready to rock and roll.
Let me see if this is still working as expected.
It is.
Okay.
All right.
Well, we have 63 HP.
We gotta go through the portal.
We gotta.
And then I'm not sure what's gonna happen.
I honestly feel like I'm kind of stuck down here.
Like I can't get out because I don't have digging capabilities.
Also, I'm kind of locked in here now.
No, I'm not.
Nevermind.
I'm kidding.
Uh, just go down.
Just go down.
So that's just called collapsed concrete.
Actually, I'll be right here.
This looks, uh, this is brickwork.
Oh, whoa!
Oh, no, I'm almost dead.
Portal, where are you?
Maybe down.
Oh, wait, there's a wand.
Can't get through there though.
Or can I?
I cannot.
No, I can't.
I was about to say, let me collapse some stuff, but that's too risky.
If it falls on me, I'm gonna die.
Just gotta find a way down now.
Down is the only way forward.
And it does not make me happy to say that.
But it is what it is.
That is that.
Okay.
How about we go down here?
Okay, this seems good.
I don't like that.
I don't like this guy.
Get away.
Okay.
God damn it.
Oh!
Weakening curse electricity.
Magic bolt with trigger.
Large magic missile.
Upwards Larpa.
Intense concentrated light.
Dude, I am very intrigued by all of this.
Uh, maybe I get rid of that.
I don't like that very much.
Maybe I don't like this either.
I definitely want to try this and that.
Then I want to get over there.
Why are there all these stores?
I didn't see this last time, I don't think, at all.
Whoa!
All right, this is fire.
Okay, portal.
Thank God.
Portal to the laboratory.
Is there a way to get back from there?
I need to heal, though.
No, I need to get to that wand.
I need to find digging.
How do I get through here?
Let's think.
I could use an earthquake shot.
Let's do it.
Let's stand at a safe distance and do this.
We can do it.
So, put this...
I don't even know where.
Throw one away.
Get rid of... Maybe get rid of lightning bolts.
Get rid of that.
Good.
Now, we're gonna use a holy lance.
And on the holy lance, we're gonna put an earthquake shot.
Make it crumble!
Actually amazing.
Yes, dude!
In small amounts, this is fine.
As long as I'm careful.
This definitely works.
Cool!
This is all collapsed, though!
Wait a minute.
Is this gonna fall down?
It's just waiting to fall down on me, isn't it?
That's a cool-looking wand.
The piercing shot makes the projectile fly through enemies, but harmful to the caster.
Okay.
Well, well, well.
Unfortunately, this is a shuffle wand.
Otherwise, this would be a crazy wand.
I don't think I want that.
I do want to collapse some things, though.
It's collapsed.
That means I can dig through it now.
Oh, wait!
I forgot there was a teleport bolt on that!
I just scared the shit out of me.
Okay, we need to do more.
We're not done.
Wait, wait, wait.
Honestly, yeah, put this here for now, I guess.
Yeah, that's fine.
Collapse it all!
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
We've got enemies.
Point!
No, no, no, no.
Come here.
That way.
Oh, wait.
Unfortunately, I can't.
Ah, here we go.
What is that?
Large spittable with timer.
Damn it!
Also a shuffle wand.
Everything is shuffled.
Every day, it's shuffled.
And that's the truth.
Oh, the red one is about to say boom, isn't it?
Boom!
There we go.
It actually is the exact same effect that happens when you leave a holy mountain.
You know, the same sort of a spell appears and everything collapses around it.
It's really neat.
I do love how this one looks, though.
Look at it.
It's massive.
Oh, I forget.
There's teleport on this.
Fuck it!
We need to heal.
Yeah, heal me up.
Let's see what we got.
Please tell me we got a digger.
What's that?
Two-way fireball thrower?
Summon tiny goat.
Another holy lance?
Oh, no.
Launch magic missile.
Shit, I don't... vacuum field?
What's that?
Sucks nearby projectiles and creatures into the middle of the field instantaneously.
Not bad.
That sounds pretty cool.
Let's see here.
Perks.
Rage-fueled levitation.
Killing an enemy makes you replenish some of your levitation power.
No.
Gas fire?
Gases near you ignite automatically.
Slime blood.
You bleed slime, but slime no longer slows you down and you have higher... Dude!
Amazing!
So what?
I don't bleed oil anymore?
That would be great!
That is fantastic.
That is only good.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah.
If that works the way I think.
Okay.
So unfortunately, here's the deal.
I don't have anything that digs here, it seems.
So what I'm gonna do is... I think I'll use my earthquake.
That one.
To get the fuck out of here somehow.
Yeah.
And the question is where to go, right?
I guess I could just go up.
But wait, am I gonna anger a god?
If I don't leave the intended way.
That's like the question here.
Right.
I may just dig up.
Let's just try that, huh?
And I have to be mindful here because...
I don't want to get hit by the falling debris.
So why should we do it?
Let's do it over here.
Let's see.
Let's just take it step by step.
It definitely works.
We can definitely get out.
The only thing I'm questioning here is, are we still in the same sort of world?
Now that we're in this... Uh-oh.
Okay.
He's not happy about that.
Are we gonna have an enemy?
Sir?
Ah!
There you are.
That's for you!
I thought he was way stronger.
I mean, sure.
All right.
This is not a problem at all.
Why was I so scared of this?
Are you kidding me?
All right.
Well, see you later, alligator.
It's gonna take a while, isn't it?
Oh!
Here's the thing.
I can go nuts and put this here.
It's scary, but it's fun.
You ready?
Nothing happened.
What the hell?
What?
Hold on.
Okay.
There we go.
It's gonna take a while.
So this is now collapsed, so I can... Ah!
Exactly.
That's what I'm scared of.
If I, like, break it loose, it's gonna fall, right?
And that's scary.
I'm really scared this is gonna fall on me.
Let me get rid of some of this.
Clean up after ourselves here.
Come on.
Ah!
We definitely need some more projectile speed on that.
Maybe we can put something else at the end.
Maybe this one.
Is that gonna do the same thing?
Oh, yeah!
Totally, I think.
Oh, yeah.
It's definitely doing things.
Come on.
Collapse.
Do something.
Oh, look at this.
It's all cold.
The tiniest change and this will all fall apart.
Question.
What if I...
Hold on.
Can I somehow do something smart here?
If I do this, this is gonna activate a digging blast at the end, isn't it?
A spark boulder casts another spell upon collision.
So when this collides up here, it casts the digging blast, but it casts it up here.
Is it digging?
Oh, yeah, definitely is.
Look, look, look.
Just need to hit a weak spot here.
Things are gonna fall on me in a second, aren't they?
Oh, that's scary.
Let me... I have an idea.
We can do something crazy here.
I'm gonna do this.
I'm gonna do that.
No, this, that, there.
Let me see.
Oh, shit.
Oh, yeah, that, that, that, that, that, that.
Whoa!
Okay, okay.
All right, that works.
Now we just need a backup wand to get the fuck out of here when things go wrong.
I just need to get the setup going.
Then I can start to rock and roll, you know?
Oh, look at that.
Maybe I can... if I just shoot up.
Even better.
What if I... No, this is fine.
This is fine.
I'm so scared of things falling on me.
But I guess I'm digging through the stuff that is supposed, supposed to fall, right?
So I'm fine in a weird way.
Oh, let's see.
Okay, that, that, that, that's bad.
That's bad.
It's about to fall down, isn't it?
Let's wait a bit.
There comes a piece.
Good thing we didn't have... get that on our head.
This is actually an insane wand.
This is doing some heavy lifting here.
Anything falling?
If I just keep shooting, whatever is falling is going to get ducked through while falling.
Oh, yep.
Get rid of it.
Oh, oh, something hit me.
That's scary.
Oh, it's just, this is like... No, let's do the falling debris before it hits you.
This is actually amazing.
Oh yeah, I'm definitely digging here.
What?
I killed something.
The hell?
What the?
Huh?
What's happening?
Oh,
I made it.
I fucking made it, dude.
We did it.
It does connect.
Look, we are back.
Oh, but wait, we don't have a proper weapon.
We gotta be careful there.
Oh, shit.
I'll be back.
Hold on.
Just wait a bit, wait a bit, wait a bit.
There.
Let's throw that shit away.
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, shit.
I don't have a weapon.
Uh, here, here, uh, there.
That's my weapon.
Here we go.
We're back.
Okay, I just need to quickly figure out how to hot swap this.
So I need to replace the freezing gaze with...
uh, that followed by this and that.
This is what I need.
No, this is what I need.
I never placed these three things with that.
That's how that works.
Okay, good.
Good, good, good.
Okay, that dude.
There's a man over there.
He needs to die immediately.
Good.
Now we can keep exploring.
Uh, I'm gonna make my way up.
Do not explore that way.
We're going straight up now.
Wow, just floating in the air like that.
That's some BS.
So it would make sense here for me to make a temporary digging.
What is this again?
Makes a potential cast copies of itself with an upwards trajectory.
That could be a digging situation, actually.
Wait a minute here.
Let's say we do this.
So this shoots.
Uh, no, wait.
This one affects this one, which then shoots and it hits the rock and activates digging blast.
But this one also has the property that it will now make copies of itself.
How many copies though?
Let's see how this works.
Wait.
Oh, wait, it only affects...
Hold on.
Oh, I'm in it.
Ah, we need this, of course.
We need earthquake.
So we need to replace this one.
Let's just make this one replaced.
Uh, let's put here.
Let me, let me, let me think.
Uh, there, there,
here, here.
Let's see.
So this one modifies the double and the double casts this one and that one.
And when this one impacts, it casts a digging blast.
Let's see how this works.
It's not doing what I... Oh, wait, we're forgetting this one.
We're forgetting the earthquake.
So we put this here, I believe.
Let's see how this works.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, nice.
Nice.
Now this is a digging one.
Holy crap.
That's actually wild.
Kill that dude.
Hey, cool yourself.
Boink.
I mean, I kind of want to explore a little bit since I have a lot of HP.
But the issue is going to be how do we get more HP if we lose it?
There was a way we healed in the pyramids.
Maybe we can do that again.
Okay, let's go up.
Let's do some digging here.
Oh, there's a guy.
He's no more.
Go!
What a digging one, man.
That is insanity.
I'm really proud of myself.
I made something great here.
I really did pat myself on the back, you know?
Stop it.
You're about to do something that I dislike.
Oh, no.
Oh, I can still have this, too.
Man, I can have everything.
I can have the cake and eat it.
It's amazing.
That guy didn't die from that.
That's unfortunate.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
I hate that this guy's following me.
I hate it.
A chest.
Wait, what's that?
Bone dust pouch.
Huh.
Do I want that?
I'm not sure.
Bone dust pouch.
Bone, bone, dust pouch.
Yeah, come on.
Oh, there's something going on there.
Let's get rid of that.
I don't like it.
Ah, holy shit.
Oh, it's on me.
Fuck, I didn't see that.
Motherfucker snuck up on me.
Unreal.
Already losing all of my HP.
This is going great.
Oh,
look at all the lava.
What the fuck?
Freeze it.
Stop the flow.
A chest.
Nice.
Thanks.
I appreciate that.
Wait, am I immune to lava?
Hold on.
I'm not.
Wait, am I?
I'm not, I'm not, I'm not.
Good to have that tested though.
I was unsure for the longest time, so.
Whoa.
What is this?
That's a lot of spells, bro.
Expanding sphere.
A slow projectile that increases its damage over time.
Okay.
Spark ball with double, dude.
Lightning bounce.
Black holes.
What else is in here?
Deadly heal.
A projectile that at first deals damage, then heals over time.
What?
Why is this a thing?
Okay.
Large magic missile.
Plasma beam cross.
God damn.
I mean, I gotta take it.
Also, look at the stats on it.
It's, it's wild.
It's really good.
This is a good wand.
Um, let's see.
Huh.
I have way too much shit.
Also, there's a ghost following me right now.
I think.
Somewhere down there.
That's gonna mess with me.
Is he following me?
Am I fine here?
Oh, thank God.
Okay, so I can chill.
I can chill and relax.
Good.
Oh, it always casts ad mana.
Even.
Oh my God.
This thing is wild.
Wow.
Okay.
We got to, we got to use this.
Replace it with that, I guess.
Uh, so here's the thing.
Let's throw away some stuff that I probably won't need.
Let's throw away that.
Vacuum.
I don't know.
Maybe we'll not do that right now.
Holy bomb.
No, thank you.
Um, maybe I'll... No, not that.
This one is cool, but no.
I'm so sorry, Lance.
I'm so sorry.
We're gonna get rid of it.
The recharge time.
I think I like that one.
Now, uh, we can replace...
Let me do this.
I think this is just a straight up better one than this one.
0.03 cast delay.
It has a higher recharge time, though.
But I have a feeling that's not gonna matter.
So, do that.
Wow.
Now we throw away some stuff we don't want.
I do want to try this.
Throw away, throw away.
Do want to try this.
In fact, since we have that now, we can probably get rid of that.
Put that there.
But wait, this casts two new spells upon collisions.
That means this one and that one.
Right.
I think.
Cast copies of the self with an upwards trajectory.
Um, right.
Maybe I'll replace this with a triple and throw this away.
Throw that away.
Nope.
Another rock.
No.
Arrow.
Black hole.
No.
Nope.
Yes.
We're not taking any of this.
Although I kind of want to grab the black hole.
Because I can just put it in here and use it in whatever circumstance I need, right?
Because I can swap anything at any time.
That's the wild part.
Okay.
Now let's put this back in here.
And because we now have an ad mana at the start, we can probably afford to put even crazier things in here that would otherwise drain.
So a slow projectile that increases damage over time.
Let's try this.
Let's get rid of this one as well.
I'm scared of it.
Go that way.
Okay.
That looks pretty dope.
I don't know how much damage it does or like 75, I guess, but is it really that cool?
We'll have to figure it out.
Deadly heal.
It does 30 damage and an unknown amount of heal.
I got to get to a easy base because I think I can do it there.
In any case, let me try and see how this works here.
This is a baseline.
I think it's the same.
It does the same thing.
It's absolutely fast.
It's super good.
We could even put this in here.
Is that going to change anything?
Let me also understand the suppression modifier.
So this should only modify that one, right?
Let's see here.
Why don't I put... hmm.
Wait a minute.
I mean, I have pretty much max mana when I shoot this thing no matter what.
It's wild.
It's the same.
Yeah, that wand is something else.
Okay, awesome stuff.
Let's keep moving.
I don't want to aggro that guy.
I'm just going to go up from here.
Whoops.
Ouch.
Let's not go that way actually.
I changed my mind.
Let's go here.
Okay, that works.
Very good.
Wait, what's going on here?
Enemies?
There you go.
Wait, am I at the top?
Break work?
This could be the top.
Let's dig.
Let's dig a little more.
Oh, this little piece fell on me.
That's annoying.
Wait a minute.
I'm actually not too happy about this digging wand.
Now that I look at it, is it actually gonna... Hold on.
If I stand below, I'm too... I think this one scares me.
See, why did that happen there?
Say what?
And is it digging at all?
Whoa.
It's like way more digging... diggy.
This is just not as good as what I had before.
It's too scary.
I need to fix.
What did I change?
I replaced that...
Motherfucker, will you stop making noise?
Over here.
There you go.
Stay there.
Now, what I had before was that one, that one, and... well, I actually only had...
I had a sparkle with one trigger, but I think it's gonna be the same.
Maybe.
Let's do this.
There.
Let's see here.
Please dig.
It's digging.
Jesus.
I'm taking some damage here.
Oh, get the pieces before they hit me.
Oh my god.
I feel like the game is lagging when I use this.
Look how much digging I did.
Damn.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Oh.
I'm stuck.
What?
What is happening?
Teleportitis?
Why?
Why do I have that?
I guess I must have gotten some liquid on me.
What the hell?
This is chaos.
I would definitely like a more, uh, less chaotic digging method, but it is what it is.
It's what I've got for now.
What I've got.
Um, can I get through there?
Probably.
You know what?
Open up there.
Mm-hmm.
Ah, shit.
Here.
Over here.
There.
Whoa.
Oh, wow.
The damp man.
It's the only real way I have of digging, though.
It sucks, but...
Actually, hold on.
I have a better idea.
I have an idea for what I can do here.
Because I need to shoot this first, right?
The earthquake, to make it all brittle.
And then I dig afterwards.
So basically, what I need is an earthquake wand, a small one, just a simple one.
And then after that, a very safe, normal digging wand at a distance.
Exactly.
So, this is gonna be my digging wand.
We're gonna put this here with that.
And then we have an extra here.
We can disregard teleport for now.
And save that one with the earthquake.
Right?
I mean, we could even put something else there, but whatever.
That should be fine.
And then we have it.
Let's see how well this digs.
See, that's lovely.
That's great.
Lovely digging.
We could also use this for the digging.
No, we can't, because it needs a trigger on it.
Let's get back here.
Look at that.
That's an amazing digger.
Wow.
Ah, I see now.
Teleportation.
You know what?
I think I broke one of the portals then.
Or the little vats of teleportation beneath a portal.
Look, it's gone!
Definitely that's what happened.
Aha!
Okay.
Dope.
Then we have this one again.
Beautiful.
Just no teleport now.
That's the only difference.
Okay, cool.
Let's go up.
Hello.
I'll find it.
I'm gonna go straight up here.
In fact, hold on.
I'm just gonna take a quick piss.
I'm bursting.
Be right back.
Okay.
Let's continue.
All right.
So we have 226 HP, which is not a lot.
My goal right now is to get to Heezy Base, because I have a theory that I can heal there.
I'll show you how.
First we gotta get there.
Looks like I've already explored this part.
That's good.
That means we can just go up.
Now that I have a much more safe way of digging, we should be fine.
As long as we do it carefully.
So weird, by the way, that this part here is like the... there's like fungus and stuff.
Like, why is that here, you know?
It's a bit odd.
No.
This way?
Oh yeah, I've definitely made... left my mark on this place.
Everything's fucking destroyed.
What am I doing?
I did that.
And I liked it.
Are we here?
Well, I guess I don't have to do it.
I can just do it here, I guess.
This doesn't have to be anywhere specific.
I used this one first.
Collapse.
And look, now we do... now we do this.
Oh no, we actually just keep collapsing.
That works.
Oh.
Just get rid of a bunch.
And when debris stops falling, that's when I know I have to go up and do some manual digging.
Hell yeah.
Look at that.
Oh, a worm was here.
Interesting.
Ow.
Oh man.
Just a little piece hit me.
Let me get the safety on the left here, I guess.
That's better.
Oh, you know what?
I have an idea.
This is what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna do this.
And then immediately after, I'm gonna start shooting this to protect myself.
Oh boy, that one's out of mana.
Maybe I use this here then.
Just to be safe, because that's scary if I run out of mana.
And this one should still work fine, right?
Because I have the add mana on it.
Look.
Hell yeah.
Is that totally fine?
And then we dig.
Good, good.
This is a great way of digging.
Hello.
I have discovered the way.
Look how safe this is.
This is actually awesome.
Yay.
We are in the jungle, baby.
We've got fun and games.
Yep.
We're back.
I kind of want to go say hello to those spiders again and just fuck them up a little bit more.
But I'm low HP.
We've got to go up one level more.
Nice.
And we're here.
I'm just gonna dig right here.
I don't care.
Gotta be a little careful still.
Yeah.
Don't get, don't get ahead of yourself here.
Oh man, the audio is starting to bug out a little bit here.
How is this not so cool?
I mean, if anything, this is the coolest digging wand ever.
It's just badass.
Whoa.
Danger, danger, danger.
Mining operations, man.
I need a helmet.
Number of days since last workplace incident.
Zero.
I don't think Ocea would be happy about all this.
Nice.
Oh, wrong one.
As long as I get out of the way, actually, it's fine.
Look, I can just go like that and then go over here and hide.
As long as I have a little overhang above me, you know.
Wait, what am I hearing here?
You hear that?
Am I hearing the portal?
Oh yeah, it's definitely getting... Oh, it's right here then.
Oh, okay.
Perfect.
I was about to say.
Whoops.
That's the wrong spell.
Didn't mean to do that, but that's fine.
We are back, baby.
This is the easy base.
Okay, now.
I guess I need to dig in here.
Rocks for everyone.
All right, time to test the theory.
Here we go, here we go.
Watch, watch, watch, watch.
Bro, this digging one is actually wild.
Okay, check this.
This thing reflects spells.
Watch.
You see that?
So, basically, I'm gonna hit myself with that.
Put it on here, I guess, for now.
Wait, what did I have here?
Yeah, I just had this, right?
I had that.
Okay, let's try it.
What?
It's not being reflected.
Oh no, what about this?
This is gonna hit me for damage first, but then...
What?
Oh, wait.
Oh, it doesn't hit me.
It goes through me.
What the fuck?
Shit!
How am I gonna heal?
I hate that I'm looking at a thing called Healing Bolt and I don't know how to utilize it.
It fucks with me.
Oh, wait, I have an idea, actually, I have an idea.
Maybe there's a drop-off on it.
If I stand in a place with enough vertical space above me, maybe it'll fall down on me.
Like here.
Let's try this.
If I shoot straight up...
No, there's no way that's coming back.
There's no way that's coming back.
That is an infinite bolt.
Hm.
That is interesting.
Well, all right.
Yes, there's no healing for me here.
Definitely want to get in there because there's a chest.
What's up, guys?
That's for you.
I can't believe he survived up there.
Blood and fire.
Oh, wait, what was in the chest?
Oh, was it the wand?
Oh, nah, don't, I don't like it.
Don't like it.
Keep going up.
What's that?
Oil.
I had enough of that.
It's time to dig up again.
Whoops.
I'll probably not stand here while that happens.
Get out of the way.
I'm going...
I'm going!
Ouch, ouch, ouch, Jesus.
Jesus.
Okay, so my new goal is to go to the pyramid because there's healing there.
Ah, the audio.
Oh, man.
It's really crackling.
There's something about... maybe it's the physics when all of this is collapsing that it can't handle it.
You know, everything slows down.
Dude, maybe I can finally go up and try and kill the boss in the hemisphere with these weapons that I have here.
Whoop!
Wait a minute.
Did I just discover something?
Oh, no, mine.
I thought for a second my normal spells would dig through the collapsed stuff.
Wait, what's... Ah, nice.
We made it.
Lovely stuff.
Uh, that looked like a shark for a second.
Oink.
Man, these enemies are nothing to me, bro.
Look how fast they die.
Hey, there's a wand and I can dig.
Hello!
There's people in there.
You like that?
Do you like rocks, sir?
That's for you.
Oh, dropper bolts.
A very heavy explosive bolt, spiral arc.
Uh, why would anyone want that?
I do wonder.
Uh, I guess I just go up.
But do I want to explore?
No, I don't because what could there possibly be in this region?
Uh, that would be better than what I have, right?
Jesus.
Oh my god, he somehow got a hit on me.
This asshole right here.
Just go up.
Oh my god, what's happening?
Oh.
Hello.
This
is pure chaos.
Man, what a trick to get back to the surface, huh?
Good.
And here we are.
Kind of want to go back into the holy mountain here just to have a peek at what I was dealing with when I was here last.
Where's the entrance?
What's that?
Concentrated man.
Damn, that's a lot.
That is a lot.
Uh, wait, wait, wait, wait, we are making.
This is okay.
You know what?
This is fine.
I'm going to go this way because we can go up over here.
Also want to see something cool?
This is how I'm going to fly.
Oh no, I threw away the holy lands.
That one has so much recoil.
That would have been the one.
Ah, shit, whatever.
But I guess I can use this.
Don't really need that right now.
Oh, there's also something in the rock here somewhere.
Maybe I'll... Here it is.
Uh, we need to... Oh shit, we need it back.
That is totally effective.
Are you up there?
Aha, look at that.
Very nice.
Ah, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
What the hell did... Oh wait, I'm bleeding slime.
That's why.
I get it.
Tablet and health.
Awesome.
Last time, wasn't there a nuke here?
That tablet went off to some other country.
I was shooting the wrong one.
I thought I was teleporting and I shot the earthquake one.
Oh man, that sucks.
I did it again.
What happened?
Are we good?
It's just, I'm just making gods angry, I guess.
Definitely don't want to fight this guy with this little HP.
So what we're going to do is... Wait, what?
Oh, oh wait.
Oh, okay.
That works.
This is sick that I can do this.
Let's just block off all this lava.
I could dig through the entirety of the lava if I wanted to.
But do I want to?
Hmm, I'm not so sure.
So hold on.
Instead of going up the normal way, I'm going to try something here.
I'm just going to go up straight from here.
Oh wait, that's not the digging one.
I need to replace it.
Nope, there.
Wait, how far can I go up here?
Okay, it's not that far.
Um, I guess I can just stand here while I do it.
Point.
Ah,
shit.
I need to teleport.
Nah, you know what?
Fuck it.
I'm just going to go the normal way.
I'm too lazy.
What?
Oh, that's a rock.
This level right here with these weapons that I have, this is hilarious.
Nothing stands a chance, but then again, nothing really stands a chance anywhere so far.
I can't speak too soon though, because there is a boss in this area that is...
By the way, it's the boss of the first area.
Why is it so difficult?
I feel like I'm missing something.
Should be easy, no?
Hey!
Stop that.
Wait, why doesn't that dig?
Oh, it does, but it's very slow.
Wow, what the hell?
Why is that so slow?
Nice!
We made it!
We made it to the surface!
It only cost us almost all of our HP.
Yup.
Okay.
Now we don't need that anymore.
Let's go back to teleporting, because that is lovely to have.
You can play music here.
Let's do it.
Ah, let's just chill for a moment.
I'm going to sip my coffee, which is cold by now.
I'm actually going to quickly heat it in the microwave, pure bag.
Ah, beautiful.
Lovely.
Okay, let's go to the pyramid.
So there's a boss in there that I have to kill before I get the HP.
So hopefully I'm not going to die.
I have 93 HP.
I think the last time I tried that boss, I had 1000 something HP.
So, hmm, you know, that'll be interesting.
Hopefully the rock...
Oh!
What?
Oh.
What's happening?
Why is everything shaking?
Why are there holes?
I don't like the shaking.
Don't like shaking.
Is the boss coming for me?
We're leaving.
What is this place, by the way?
It's like a huge bone skull, but it's a bone wall, I guess, but...
Yeah, no clue.
Not a clue.
I feel like I should try and figure out how the fuck this healing works.
Increase lifetime.
Upwards.
Shit, man.
Okay, here we are.
It's the pyramid.
Let me in.
I have business to attend to in these parts.
I entered the pyramid.
Oh, that is coming onto something below.
That's fine.
Go.
Have fun.
Have fun down there, Rock.
Boink.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Stupid rocks.
Oh, it's trying to go to the...
It was homing in on the scorpion.
That's amazing.
Hold on.
Don't go down.
We're going up.
It's at the top, no?
These are him, Mrs. No.
I think so.
I'm ready to get my ass kicked now.
That's fine.
I may actually get my ass kicked here.
That's it.
There we are.
We actually made it.
This is... That was fast.
So I... Whoa!
Bastard.
Didn't even see you.
Wait a minute.
There we go.
Fuck off.
This is what you do.
You just shoot it upwards and hope it hits.
Oh!
I didn't mean to activate it yet.
Oh, no.
Oh, damn.
Here we go, I guess.
Uh... Wait, I can't get in here?
Oh, shit.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay, so this guy, he opens up and I have to shoot him.
Can I rock him?
I definitely can rock him.
I can rock his world.
I like... You like rocks, dude?
I have plenty.
Plenty to go around.
Just look at all the rocks on him.
I'm just gonna let those rocks do their job while I hang out back here, okay?
Exquisite me.
Are you gonna be okay?
There we go.
Shoot the rocks up there.
Up you go.
Hit him.
Let me try and see if I can.
If he gets close to me here, I'm gonna shoot him with the shotty.
Bastard.
Let's freeze this lava just to be safe.
In fact, let me freeze you for a second.
Yeah, you like that?
Hold on, I can actually hot swap.
How about we try this?
Is that gonna do much?
Sir?
Come here.
Come to me.
Is it hitting anything?
I'm so scared.
I just need him to come back here so I can hit him with this new weapon.
Oh, there comes a rock.
Return to sender.
Well, I'm the sender.
Sir, where are you?
Wait there?
Follow you?
Oh no, I don't dare anything.
Wait, I killed him?
Hallelujah!
Fuck yeah!
Wait, where's the healing?
Where's the promised healing?
Uh...
Rotate towards foes?
What's the difference between this and homing?
I mean, sure.
Whoop!
You bastard.
Cool.
Let me switch this up just so I know what to expect.
Okay, so we have random modifier spell.
What is it with these random spells?
Why would I cast random spells?
Now this one, this is the interesting part here.
One in the pond, one in the tree, one on the ledge, and one under the sun.
I know there's a music thing in the pond.
There's one in the tree.
The ledge, I don't know.
I think I understand the sun.
Actually, I don't.
I have to explore more.
But it's gotta be referring to the music stuff.
There's just no other way.
Like there's one in the pond, what else could it fucking be, right?
Where's the healing?
Did I just remember wrong?
Did I not get healing here last time?
Shit.
I feel like I did.
I definitely killed a boss and got healing.
That is what I remember.
I mean, I'll take this.
Just a half.
And maybe I will...
No, I will leave this book here.
I can go kill something.
Hmm.
You know what?
I'm gonna go explore more of the surface.
Yeah.
Let's just try that.
What is that?
Kinda just wanna go out here, you know?
Fortunately, I can't dig there.
You know what?
That's just...
No, I'm gonna do it.
Oh, wait.
Is that it?
Is that the healing?
I saw something here.
No, wait.
That's just the...
Oh, wait, wait.
I remember now.
It wasn't here.
It was somewhere else where I found the healing.
It was like somewhere in a little area, in a little room.
Somewhere.
Nice.
That's good.
The necessity of concealing the art is one of the chief anxi- Ah, I've read this one before.
I am the most uninitiated person ever.
Okay.
Keep going.
What does that even mean?
So, whenever I pick up an orb, everything shakes and I hear a growling.
Right?
Interesting.
Oh, wait a minute.
Didn't I already try going all the way to the right?
And then there was just a big wall.
There's this thing.
Essence Eater.
So, if I shoot it, it just disappears.
And I don't want that.
So, I'm just gonna leave it for now.
Maybe there's something I can do with it later.
And what's going on with this?
What if I remove the weights?
From this.
Is anything gonna happen then?
Let me excavate it.
Excavation!
Oh, it's not destroyed.
On.
Notice how dark it's become here.
Okay, that doesn't do anything.
Man, where the fuck did I find that healing?
Remember?
Oh, wait, was it here?
I think this is it.
Wait, what's that?
Watchtower, this is it.
I think this is where I found the heal.
All the way at the top.
That was a little chamber, remember?
That must have been where I found it.
And dude, lava?
We don't care about lava because we have this.
So, here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna do this.
Lava!
I didn't mean to make a collapse.
Wrong one, wrong one, wrong one.
I feel so powerful.
Ow!
Don't stand on the lava!
You dummy!
Man, I gotta block that right now.
Block it!
There we go.
No more lava shall flow here.
Same here.
Stop it.
Actually, just do this.
And then we dig like that.
Yeah, much better.
Well, we're not gonna get our...
Hold on.
Maybe it's better from the top.
I start from up here.
Like that.
Oh, but then I have to...
That's fine, that's fine, that's fine.
Nice.
Wait, what?
Oh, no.
Oh, that's right.
This was just giving me a hint that there's something above the pond.
Wait a minute.
Is that true though?
Mountain here?
Is that the starter mountain?
What mountain is that?
Could be the...
No, it's way too uneven to the pyramid, no?
You know what?
I honestly...
I think I was healing after the boss that I just killed, and I just didn't get a heal this time.
I think it's just RNG.
Maybe I didn't get a heal.
You know?
So, I'm kind of at a loss here for what to do.
I don't know how to heal myself.
That's painful, man.
Whoops, didn't mean to do that.
Thought it was teleport.
I am gonna walk west.
Actually, you know what?
I'm gonna walk as west as I can now.
New plan.
Completely new plan.
We're gonna switch things up.
Try something completely different now.
Just keep walking.
We know there's snow at some point, but we don't know what happens after that.
Off the teleport.
But imagine having a...
Not a small one, but a normal one here.
You could go really far.
What?
Why did it pause?
I didn't click anything.
That was weird.
Oh!
No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Nope, we're not doing that.
We're not, not...
What?
Why are you...
Hold on, why is the game pausing?
Am I clicking something?
What am I clicking?
I don't understand what I'm doing.
Okay, so that's the pond.
See, this gotta be the mountain we saw on the picture, no?
It looks exactly like it.
The way it's sort of...
Okay, I'm not so sure, actually.
This part wasn't there.
But I'm going this way now.
That is...
What is that?
Also, can I just dig here?
No.
Don't want to take that, obviously.
There's, there's more things here every time.
I kind of want to go back into the vods and check what this looked like at the start.
Because this, this wasn't here, I don't think.
And that!
This one I remember.
That one I remember.
Maybe I remember this one too.
Whoops.
Money.
I mean, music.
Snowy wasteland.
And we, then we also have this.
The air feels freezing.
There's, I don't want to go in there, but there's a wand I can take there.
Even though I know I can't take fall damage, I'm still sort of scared of it, because I have 55 HP.
So this thing.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
There's something I wanted to do!
Hold on, I'm going to go back.
Ah, I'm so...
Ah, fuck, I should have remembered this.
I want to go back to the top of the mountain.
I have things I want to try here.
It's actually important.
It's important for testing reasons, because I won't always have the things I have on me right now.
Is this gonna work?
Oh my god!
I'm gonna try and put this stuff up here.
I found a little moon.
This tiny celestial object has a strong gravitational pull.
You like water?
You're gonna suck up the water?
What about this one?
I'm not being rewarded for my curiosity.
Damn it!
Uh, well, shit.
That was pretty much what I wanted to test.
But then there's also...
It also says you feel like kicking it.
Oh, but kicking it does nothing, because I'm telekinesis-ing it now.
Oh, but so now it's inactive.
Runestone of magma.
See, now it's active.
I wonder if this will repel magma.
Or something.
If I'm next...
Okay, if I'm next to lava...
Whoops.
I will try to use this.
Maybe that will do something.
You know?
Anyway, let's go.
Wait, what's that?
Oh, gold.
I gotta be careful here.
There's enemies somewhere.
So, let me actually grab this one then.
Maybe I'll throw this one away.
I'm gonna take this with me.
It is interesting.
I know you can sort of dig through snow with it and stuff.
Wait, what if I hit this with it?
Burn the runestone of magma.
Wait, what if I put this one up here instead?
How do I just...
Okay, it has a life of its own?
Pretty neat.
What the hell happened here?
Uh...
Yeah, so...
Okay, ancient laboratory?
I definitely want to explore this place.
I haven't explored this yet.
But I can't do it with 55 HP.
Those enemies look insane.
I gotta explore that place.
Oh, it's getting dark again.
I've been here before.
I remember that flag.
Another essence here.
Fuck does that mean?
Let me try and release this here.
Wait, did I just lose HP?
Bro, I just lost HP from releasing this.
What the hell?
Oh, you know what?
Let me try something.
Oh wait, just holding it sucks things in.
That's pretty cool.
Okay, that just damages it.
All right.
Oh, it's very dark now.
I don't think I've gone this far before.
I'm scared.
What am I gonna find?
Whoops, I'm sorry.
Look at that.
Nothing in there.
Okay.
Gotcha.
Oh,
wait, I have been here.
I think I died here.
I don't want to go down that either.
I just want to keep going west.
Yeah, this is...
I haven't been here yet.
This is as far as I've ever been.
My screen is shaking.
Why is it shaking?
What's happening here?
I'm taking my way through the mountain.
Or the glacier, I guess.
Enter...
Lake?
Oh my god.
Alchemist's note.
Here, I'm safe.
I am safe.
I left the others behind, and I have locked my research, so that only those with real understanding can reach it.
I should not worry.
As long as I resist the temptation, I will be safe.
I know my limits.
Here, I am far away from them.
I should not worry.
The temptation to keep going.
To keep going through the holy mountains and...
play the game sort of.
I have locked my research, so that only those with real understanding can reach it.
But wait.
Are we talking about the research notes we found?
Only those with real understanding can reach it.
I reached it.
I found it.
If that is indeed his notes.
Weird.
Okay.
Look at the lights and the ceiling.
Pretty neat.
Well, okay.
Oh, there's something light down there.
What is lighting?
What?
Whoa!
What the fuck is that?
There's a portal?
Portal to a far away land.
Okay.
We gotta try that immediately.
Let's try not to die here.
That works.
Is that where he locked his research?
Say what?
That's not very far away, sir.
I would say that's very close.
What was that?
Okay, I'm confused.
I'm confused here.
Say what now?
All right, fine, whatever.
Let's keep moving a little bit.
What happens when this fills with water?
It's soon full.
Wait a minute.
Fill it up.
What happens when we've covered the portal with water?
Let's see what happens.
I'm gonna sip.
Tears, everybody.
Hold on, I have an idea.
So this one says, I left the others behind.
That could mean he went through the portal.
And I have locked my research so that only those with real understanding can reach it.
That could mean that I don't have real understanding.
Maybe I need real understanding to get in here.
But what would that entail?
Real understanding.
He's an alchemist.
Maybe I need to...
Wait, is that portal getting smaller?
No, no, it's not.
Never mind, never mind.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on.
I know my limits.
Here, I am far away from them.
Far away from whom, though?
Is there anything below?
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's happening here?
Hold on, I have an idea, actually.
What if I take this with me?
Let me get rid of...
No, let me get rid of...
You know what?
Unstable teleportation?
Fuck off.
Grab that.
The same.
Okay, good.
Now, we try to go down here.
Break that open.
Good.
Now we wait.
That's gonna suck in.
All right.
Okay, so that also leads back up here.
Hold on, I need my teleport.
What else is down here?
Shit, I'm scared.
Dude, drain this entire place.
I have just drained a hall of water.
Oh, no, it's gonna freeze.
Oh, no.
That was not my intention.
Oh, the game is lagging.
Oh, the physics, it can't simulate it.
That was wild.
All right, all right.
Let's chill here for a moment.
Oh, hold on a minute.
Actually, actually, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
This could be the pond on the image we saw.
So I'm gonna try and go up.
Oh, wait.
Wait a minute.
Look.
That's this one.
Oh, wait, what's happening?
Hello?
I'm doing something.
Something's happening.
Nice.
Is anything up here?
Are we just gonna read the fucking clouds again?
Hold on, I'm gonna go back down.
Okay, try again.
Look, it's doing something.
Let me just try and stay like this for a while.
Let's just wait.
So this, by the way, could mean the ledge.
You know, the musical instrument.
One in the pond.
One under the sun.
One on the ledge.
And one on the tree.
Come on, do something.
Wait, I feel like the weather is changing.
It's getting more foggy, look.
Hey, come on.
No, wait, never mind.
Let me throw.
What if I go to the left?
Oh, wait a minute.
What if I do this on some of the other ones?
Do this?
I kind of want to go to the other musical instruments and do this now.
You know?
One on the ledge, done.
Then we just need to find one under the sun.
Come on, do something.
Do I need to... intensity?
Come on.
Ow, I hurt myself with it.
Okay, new plan.
We're going to try and leave it here.
Fuck!
What if I stand on it?
Hold on.
Yo!
Look!
What the hell is happening?
Looks like there's an invisible platform that can only be accessed using this.
Grab it.
Okay, you know what?
I'm going to try and go to one of the other ones.
But I have 46 HP.
Man.
I mean, we can get to the tree.
The tree's not that far.
We have to try and see what happens over there.
So there's something about this eye.
And that is intriguing.
Go up here.
I think the next one is on the tree.
So...
Should be too bad.
In fact, maybe I should just start having this equipped to see if anything will appear.
You know?
Oh, you know what?
It kind of makes sense.
What am I holding right now?
An eye.
This eye only sees certain things.
You know?
And it saw that platform there.
Maybe that is always there, but it's like revealed now.
Or like, physicalized.
It's made real, sort of.
Oh.
Oh, fuck.
That scared me.
So it was on top of this, by the way.
It was on top of this pillar.
Hmm.
What if I...
Dude.
Anything happening now?
Okay.
Whoops!
Ah!
That was the wrong button.
Didn't mean to do that.
Imagine that just killed me.
That would have been funny.
All right, here we go.
Run 1 HP!
Oh my god.
Dude.
Dude, it's fucking over.
I need to heal so bad.
I gotta find out how to heal with this.
Oh my god.
Let's see here.
Can I do something?
Can I somehow...
Can I...
Fuck!
This one is not gonna be good, because that's deadly.
Uh...
Shit.
I don't know what to do.
Dude!
I think I know what to do.
We need a spell called Delayed Spellcast.
You know, we start it, and then we run into the projectile.
And then it shoots.
Delayed is what we need.
I found that one before, but I don't have it.
I mean, I didn't find it in this run, I don't think, but it exists.
It's a thing.
That is how I'm gonna do it.
Okay, so it has not...
Oops, didn't mean to shoot that one.
It has nothing to do with the musical instrument, then.
It's something to do with the pillar it was on.
That's actually good to know.
That's important information.
So let me try and experiment some more with the pillar.
Or the ledge, I guess.
Could also be the one under the sun, even though...
How does that make sense?
What?
No, no.
I equipped the wrong thing.
I feel like my keyboard is doing things I'm not telling it to today.
Also, it's pausing the game randomly.
So I need to take one point of damage and I'm done.
That means, do not let go of the eye when I'm holding it.
For God's sakes, do not let go of it.
Huh?
Yeah?
Well, come on.
Do...
Do not go down there.
Just don't do it.
I mean, I could technically experiment with this...
Uh...
In the beginning of a game.
Right?
I don't need to be late game to do this stuff.
Okay, let's see here.
What if I do it from down here?
Actually, wait a minute.
It has nothing to do with the pillar at all.
It's just, when I have it equipped, it appears here.
Wait a goddamn second.
Oh!
Shit.
Uh...
Can I hot swap?
Wait a minute.
Oh...
Dude.
Ah ha ha!
Where am I going?
Don't take me to the clouds.
Because I'm gonna instantly die if that's the case.
I see clouds in the background.
I'm stuck.
Yeah!
Okay, there we go.
Uh...
See ya!
Have fun.
I just see gold falling.
Oh!
Man, good thing those rocks don't hurt me, huh?
Okay, well, I'm coming back here later for sure.
When I have more HP.
Yeah.
That is, that ain't happening.
We are gonna...
Excuse me?
Who are you?
Are you the Alchemist?
Is this your home?
Probably not, right?
Anyway, where did I leave that book?
Oh, it's on me.
I'm an idiot.
Oh, dude, actually!
Wait a minute.
Look at that!
Is that a book, or is it a tablet?
Kinda looks like a tablet?
Maybe I need to bring a tablet here.
What?
Do I need to do something with the book?
Put it in the spot?
Hmm.
I think I need to bring a tablet here.
But which tablet?
I'm gonna go this way now.
Dude, I am draining the...
There's a sheep.
Hello, sir.
You like rocks?
Man, I just split that sheep in three.
Ooh.
What is that?
Oh.
What's happening?
Nope!
Ah, boss!
It's a boss!
No!
Oh, no!
We can't do it!
One HP?
Oh, my god.
Watch me do it.
I'm gonna fucking own this guy.
All we need is to shoot rocks.
Wait, what?
Uh...
Where are you?
Hello?
I don't know why I did that.
I feel mean now.
Wait a minute.
Isn't this a real statue from real life?
I feel like this exists somewhere in the world.
Am I crazy?
I feel like that is a real thing.
Oh, fuck.
I'm so sorry.
I just...
I'm sorry, I have to kill them.
I'm afraid.
Maybe they'll kill me.
If they hit me for one, I'm dead.
Just one and I'm dead.
Kind of weird to see, like, deers and shit here.
Oh, man.
Oh!
What is that?
Oh, right.
It freezes the water.
That's unfortunate.
Got him.
Why is all that water disappearing?
Wait, what?
What's happening?
Is this eating up the water?
What is it?
Worm blood.
Wait, what the fuck is going on there?
What's with the reaction?
That's happening here.
Worm blood.
Say what now?
I'm gonna go this way.
Oh, wait.
Did we reach the end?
Not on my watch.
I'm squeezing as much as I can out of this 1 HP before I croak.
Actually, there is a way to heal.
It would be to just explore the world and hope to find healing, you know?
In a wand.
It's... it's not really great.
But it... uh-oh.
Yeah, okay.
So that just leads back up there.
Gotcha.
I have another idea.
I'm gonna...
because I have the capability, I'm gonna dig.
And when I say dig, I mean really dig.
Dig until the game doesn't let me dig anymore.
Watch.
I'm gonna...
do this.
It's digging time, baby!
Oh, another!
Okay, okay.
Jesus.
I'm here fucked up.
Oh, shit!
I kept thinking my second one was a teleport and I kept breaking rocks.
God damn it!
Oh well.
That was a fun way to go out, though.
Of all the possibilities here, I'm not mad about that.
That's okay.
I like this death a lot.
We're gonna save that.
Well, this was almost a win.
Well, I could have won, I guess, if I wanted to.
I was at the last stage.
I could have walked in and killed the guy, I think, pretty handily.
But instead, I chose to explore.
And in the process, it cost me my life.
But you know what?
I learned a bunch of new shit.
Apparently, there's a stairway to heaven, if you use the eye.
That's one thing.
And I think my next objective is going to be...
Well, trying to get up there, of course, and see what's going on.
And kill those people.
And then also go to the ancient laboratory.
Or whatever that place was.
In the snowy place.
That's what I'm gonna do.
Return to game.
I can go for a bit longer.
Let's see what we got here.
That's a great start, because look at this.
Oh, you know what, man?
I'm gonna be so...
What do you call it?
It's... optimal this time.
I'm not actually gonna grab the health up there.
Just in case I find the perk that will grant me more health every time I take one of those.
So I'm saving that.
As nuts as that sounds.
Because I want to be...
The air feels heavy?
What the fuck does that mean?
The air feels heavy.
Wow.
Sir.
Do not do that to me.
There we go.
Boink.
Show me the goods.
What do we have up here?
Oh, there's a bunch of gold hanging up there.
Wait.
Toxic rock?
I don't like that.
Why is that here?
That scares me.
Me no likey.
The hell?
What is happening here?
I wonder if anything I do in previous runs will affect next runs.
I'm inclined to say no.
But I'm not sure.
Hamis!
It's been a while.
What's up, Hamis?
Hand over your lunch money.
Um, I could get through there if I want to.
I have nine more shots of the good stuff.
Man, I was like, I'm just gonna grab that and throw it, but I can't.
I don't have telekinesis anymore.
That is such a good perk.
Didn't.
Oh, dude, another thing I want to do.
I want to find a persistent light source.
And then I want to go into the dark.
I don't...
Is it here or the next stage?
There's a place to the west where everything is super dark.
And you cannot light it up by going in there.
You have to have a light.
Remember when we had the rock that lighted up?
That's what I'm talking about.
That's where I want to go as well.
What is that?
Lava potion?
I don't think so, buddy.
A bunch of gunpowder.
Hamis!
Oh, wait, that's not a hamis.
That's a horta.
And I have to remember, I'm not immune to fire anymore.
So let's be careful around fire.
In fact, I'm doing really well so far.
It's actually wild.
Why
did so much fucking get set on fire here?
What happened?
There was no fucking fire when I went and then it dropped on me.
The chance of that.
It's okay, though.
Just five HP.
Then again, HP is actually one of the most valuable things in this game.
Like, every single point of damage you take is actually significant.
Even in the late game, you know?
That shit can come back and haunt you later.
Could mean the difference between taking a heal in a holy mountain and not and saving it.
That's a big dealio, friendlio.
Hamis!
Gorta!
I will learn the names of all the enemies.
I'm kidding, I won't.
Wasn't that a good joke?
Comedy tour soon.
Coming up.
Somewhere near you.
Collapsed mines.
Okay.
Nothing of interest that way.
Haven't you found a wand yet?
Isn't that kind of unusual?
Oh, wow.
We charge on that, it takes a while.
Oh!
Is that a shotgun man?
Jesus!
What the hell just happened there?
Well, I can shoot too.
That's annoying.
Have a rain of fire there.
All right.
I think this is the portal.
I mean, we could go through.
Yo-ho!
That
was a close one.
There's one really scary dude in this place.
Somewhere.
What is that?
Pheromone.
Give me that.
Whoa!
Ow!
You motherfucker!
That guy has HP!
Yeah, let's not go down there.
Not worth it.
Speaking of preserving HP.
Think about it like this.
If I use one of those HP heals in the Holy Mountain, it will just max out my HP, right?
So if my max HP is 100, it will only heal 50.
Let's say I don't take any damage in the first area, right?
That is so important later on, because that heal could have been like a thousand heal.
So, actually, the earlier...
My God, how much HP does this frog have?
Damn!
So, anyway, every point of damage you take in the very early area is actually a big deal.
More so than the late.
I don't know if I should take this or save it if I find one of those perks.
I think... no.
I think we should take it.
I think I've changed my mind on that.
We should take those.
There's... there is such a thing as too optimal, you know?
Everyone is optimal until they get a fist in their face and the run ends.
Damn it.
I got hit.
Frogs!
I think I'm dead!
Well, there it is.
There it is!
Fucking frogs and fire!
Frogs and fire.
Those are the two hardest enemies in this game.
I'm actually gonna quit here.
I'm just gonna... I'm just gonna save the next run for next time.
What's up, people?
I have a bit of time.
By the way, I don't think I should be too scared of spoilers anymore.
I mean, I already completed the game, right?
And I guess there's still stuff to be found, but if anything, it's gonna be so obscure.
People are gonna... I mean, still, don't spoil, of course.
I'm just saying that.
What I'm saying is, maybe I shouldn't wait like 30 seconds until I read the chat.
Anyway, I'm gonna read now.
Loved your 1 HP run?
Yeah.
I can't believe I survived with 1 HP.
That was actually insanely lucky.
Do you take notes like a checklist?
Yes.
Yep, I do.
I do.
I have a notebook right here.
I'm also gonna write down the stuff that I said today.
I'm gonna explore the ancient laboratory and all that.
And I want to go on those platforms.
There are many things I need to do.
You don't need spoilers.
You need experiments.
Exactly, Lavy.
That was a crazy run, man.
And it was the run right after I beat the game, too.
Like, just straight up back into it, getting a sick run.
1 HP is all you need.
I mean, you're right.
If you play perfectly.
I did rock those enemies, man.
I liked the part where you were playing space invaders against falling debris.
That's actually so true.
I wonder if anyone's ever done that before, the way I did that, you know?
There's probably way better ways of doing this, but...
I used what I had at my disposal, you know?
People do no hit runs.
Of course they do.
That doesn't surprise me at all.
People are crazy.
I wonder how many tries that takes on average before you beat the game.
By the way, when you're capturing your death gif, you can change how much is included by clicking on the frames at the top.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
I know that.
The thing I would wish, though, is that it only records slightly before my death and after.
Because if I wait too long and I look at the statistics and then I click save death replay, it doesn't even save my death.
I feel like that... isn't that like a crazy oversight?
How is that not an obvious change to make?
I don't understand that.
When would you ever want to save the part after you died?
Ever?
You know?
I have gone into this game without looking anything up.
I'm over 300 attempts with no wins for whatever that's worth.
I mean, are you having fun with it?
That's the only question.
If you're having fun with it, and I guess you are, otherwise you wouldn't have done 300 attempts, then everything's fine.
Then don't worry about it.
Honestly, I don't even care that I got a win.
The funniest part is just playing this game, man.
So I think that's cool.
Seems like you're enjoying it.
Deeply disturbed.
I love your name.
I'm loving every one of my failures.
That's the spirit.
Good man.
There's a keybind to watch replays even when you aren't dead.
Oh!
Really?
Okay, that's actually good knowledge there.
What is the keybind?
I would love to know that.
Because sometimes some things happen and you're like, what the fuck just happened?
And you would love to see that in like instant replay.
Light night.
You can change in the setting how long the recording is and even enable the recording when you're not dead.
Okay, yeah.
I know that I can change it to...
so that it saves a longer GIF.
I already did that actually.
I increased the megabytes that it saves.
But I did not know that I could save anything at any time.
F11.
Okay, thanks.
Awesome.
I'm gonna remember that.
Liminal Roar.
I played mostly blind and took 200 hours for my first win.
But I loved every hour and it was like over 400 deaths.
Damn.
You must have loved a lot of that, yeah.
But here's the thing.
People are a little bit different in the way they approach games, right?
I assume some people would just not play very safe at all and just sort of...
just go crazy, you know?
Just jump in, shoot everything without a care in the world and hope for some good spells.
That's a way to do it and that's fun, I guess.
And then there's people that do it a little slower.
So naturally those people are gonna have less deaths, you know?
But as long as they're having fun, that's all that matters.
Fuck it, we ball play style?
Exactly, you know?
So anyways, I started blasting.
Basically my wand that I had just before.
The one that shot in like a...
Well, the spammy wand that I had.
I had 650 deaths, but a lot of those were restarts because I was using the mod that gives starting loadouts.
Oh, okay.
Steam will add background recording.
It's in beta and I think it's very nice for Noita.
Three settings to choose from.
I've heard about this!
It was advertised to me through Dota, actually.
I have 800 deaths and do good runs and still no wins.
I just don't bother.
Well, yeah, exactly.
If you're just enjoying the game.
And let's be honest, the end of this game isn't really anything spectacular, is it?
I mean, the game just sort of stops.
And you kind of wish it didn't and you wanted to continue.
Honestly, I don't even see why I would ever end the game again and go for another win.
You know?
Why would I ever do that when I can explore all kinds of other things?
It doesn't make sense to me.
The end is never the end, is never the...
Where's that from?
I feel like I've seen something like that before.
Is that a common meme or a reference to something?
There's a lot more to do in this game than just go down and kill the end boss.
Yeah, that's the feeling I get.
Exactly.
So I don't understand why would you just want to do that every time?
Unless it's fun to do that.
I mean, I can imagine it would be fun to do like challenges like a speed run.
How fast can you actually beat the game?
You know?
And I guess people do that.
Stanley Parable game?
Oh yeah, that's actually on my list as well.
Yeah, the moment you reach the end, you never finish in this game as it's just unsatisfying.
Well, it was a little satisfying to get that win and get that little one on my stats.
But other than that, I would have loved to do more.
And I'm gonna do more.
Stanley Parable is amazing.
I've heard a lot of people say that.
The random seed speed runs for Noita can be jaw-dropping, especially all boss runs.
That sounds fun.
Do you want to know what the things are on top of the tree?
No.
I will ask if I ever want to know.
I will make it very clear.
The game is literally infinite.
Yeah, like so many other games.
Some games are just made to be played forever, you know?
Well, until you don't have fun anymore.
No, I have not played Stanley Parable.
But I have heard the end is never the end is never the end thing somewhere on the internet before.
I didn't know it was from that.
YuriForged has a video on a two-second speed run?
What?
That's gotta be using some kind of glitch.
There's no way.
Right?
Hey, space lover.
Yeah, this is the end of the stream.
I'm just chilling right now.
I had a very...
I would say a very fun death at the end there.
Or did I?
Did I just make that up?
Your audio is going crazy right now?
What?
There was a pretty demon static.
Okay.
That's interesting.
Usually when that happens, I can hear it too.
But I didn't hear anything.
That's weird.
You heard no static, sad face.
I'm sorry.
Next time I'm sure you're gonna hear it.
Singing bowl spirits are jealous.
Honestly, I really enjoy this background sound of just rain and thunder.
Dude, that would be my ideal place to live.
Somewhere with a lot of glass in the...
Somewhere off-site, you know, away from civilization and just have the rain constantly.
Hitting that glass and just...
Oh my god.
Just the thought of that relaxes me completely.
My ears are not attuned.
You have rain and thunder right now?
I'm jealous.
I had that the other day.
Sometimes I just go over and lie in my bed and listen to it.
I open the window.
There's a two-second one using an exploit and an almost impossible to make wand build.
But it doesn't count for actual speedrun leaderboards.
Damn.
Two seconds.
How is that even possible?
But wait.
So wait, it's not actually a glitch.
It's a...
It's a wand you make?
But you wouldn't see the stars if it would rain all the time?
Ah, you're right, space lover.
That's true.
I guess I would love a mix between the two, you know?
What is that icon next to Furyforged?
Raging Wolfhelm.
There's so many things about Twitch I don't understand.
Like, where did you even get that icon?
It's a wand and it's pretty much a glitch.
Okay.
Yeah, I was about to say two seconds.
How's that even...
I mean, I guess you would have to murder the last boss and...
Yeah, I guess you would just have to murder the last boss.
And then click on the button.
Where you go to the work or whatever.
That's dongerslams, sob emojis.
Okay.
That one is from watching Elden Ring when the DLC dropped.
I didn't even know you could attain these symbols from doing that.
What's your favorite OST from your channel playthroughs?
Oh, man.
That's a hard question.
Shit.
Okay, I'm gonna give you some, but they're not necessarily gonna be my favorite, okay?
It's just the ones that come to mind right now.
I really liked the music in the Talos principle.
Especially that first area.
Dude, I've been living for that after finishing that game.
Holy shit.
I've been listening to that a lot.
I absolutely love that music.
Obviously, Outer Wilds.
Oh, man.
I can't even think.
What else did I play?
Oh, man.
What's the one called?
The Danish game.
Inside.
Inside has some incredible music.
Trying to think what else...
What else did I actually play?
Why is my brain short-circuiting right now?
I really like the music in tunic as well.
Undertale, man.
Undertale.
Of course.
Undertale music?
Damn, son.
I was...
Dude, throughout that whole time I was playing the game, I was just head nodding.
Head banging.
Not head banging, but you know.
What's it called?
Head bobbing.
I was bobbing my head to the music.
That's the word.
Yeah, you had a music appreciation counter for Undertale.
You guys are fucking hilarious.
I don't even notice that I do these things sometimes, so it's kind of funny that you take notice of that.
Have you looked up stuff about Undertale that you might have missed?
No, but I think I've gotten a little spoiler from the comments about stuff that's still there to do.
But that's fine.
I mean, maybe one day I'll try that.
The other path, if you know what I mean.
Not to spoil anything for anyone in the chat.
Stank facing?
Yeah, maybe a bit of that too.
I actually recently learned about that term.
I didn't know that was a thing.
But it's mostly when people do freestyle stuff.
And they're like, oh yeah, that was a sick bar.
Tunics OST is so good.
It is.
It really is.
That game in general is so good.
Did you play that Fury Forged?
Undertale is a nostalgia simulator game.
I've heard people say that, but here's the thing.
So based on the comments I've gotten on YouTube, and also on Twitch, I guess.
That game is apparently like a love letter of sorts to similar games.
The issue is though, I have never played those similar games.
You know the game where you have, when you're fighting one of these enemies and they're in the top of the screen.
And you see them bobbing up and down, you know, like a fighting game.
And then you have a set of options to attack or defend or use an item or something.
I have never played those games.
Undertale was the first game that had that for me.
And I know that Pokemon is one of them that do that same thing.
Yeah, it's one of my favorites.
Nice, me too.
When I first started that game, it felt a little weird.
Like I wasn't sure what to think of it.
Like in the first 10 minutes, but after that I was immediately hooked, you know?
Tuning is so good.
Turn based?
No, no, I have played turn based games before.
But I mean like the, you know, that type of game where like, oh, your attack wasn't very effective.
Pokemon style, I guess.
It was really funny that you didn't know what random encounters were.
Outed yourself as never playing a JRPG before.
That's not true, I have played a JRPG.
I've played some of Persona 5.
So I guess, oh wait, that is actually kind of similar then.
But that's like 3D, it's not quite the same where you have like the little preview in the top and then the options in the bottom.
But it is kind of similar, I guess.
So hold on, I have actually played one.
Yeah.
Persona 5.
I never completed it because it's such a long game.
And I had other things happen and then I couldn't get back into it.
That one doesn't have random, no.
You can see the enemies walking around and you approach them.
You guys keep mentioning Dunk or Slam.
Is he like a speedrunner?
Doing a 100% run and was about 50 hours in and the Noita devs released a patch.
Contains some things and ruining his 100% run.
One of the spells was Touch of Grass.
Okay.
That sucks.
50 hours in a run in Noita.
That's insane.
What dungeon did you leave on?
Um, it was...
I wanna say a bank?
Or shortly after the bank?
I think I was quite far, but I'm not sure.
I do intend to finish it one day though.
Because I absolutely love the music in that game.
And the art style.
He's kind of...
Oh yeah, actually you told me this before.
He's kind of a Noita guru, that's right.
He's the Noita guru.
Okay.
He's the biggest Noita player?
You mean like, is he just the biggest, like he's the best?
Or everyone just knows about him.
I told him to Touch of Grass.
Furyforged is a Noita guru?
Are you a Noita guru?
Furyforged.
Do you know everything there is to know about this game?
I think you might enjoy Slay the Spire.
A deck building roguelike, similar to Inscription.
I mean, if it's similar to Inscription, I'm already sold.
Inscription was amazing.
I loved Inscription.
Might not fit to do a playthrough because of that.
Oh, really?
I mean, I like gameplay focused games.
That's fine.
I mean, that's purely what Noita is, right?
I mean, there is a bit of lore that I found so far.
And I definitely want to explore more of the lore.
But so far, it's mostly gameplay.
But oh boy, is the gameplay good.
The gameplay of Noita is unbelievably good.
I might know a lot about it.
I'm working on a run that is over 150 hours long.
Alchemy is my main thing.
What?
150 hours?
Oh man, that's crazy.
That just made me even more hyped about the game.
I'm not gonna lie.
The fact that you can do that...
A 150 hour run means there's gotta be an insane amount of content.
You just excited me.
But what's to come?
How far do I record in advance?
Usually, it depends how busy I am in real life.
But usually between three and ten episodes ahead.
Noita is one of the greatest games...
Dude, so far it's just pure fun.
I've already had so many moments where I thought, holy shit, I've never experienced that in a video game before.
Like, here's an example.
The other day, I was in the Heezy base.
And I was just shooting my wand, you know?
Be like, what's over there?
And I hit something.
And then out of fucking nowhere, one of those propane tanks came flying towards me because it was leaking and Newton's Third Law and all that, right?
And it just flew around me.
And I got so fucking scared because I didn't know what was gonna happen there.
I only knew that they hurt.
And it felt like it was following me.
And that just seemed like such a random ass encounter.
But it was so cool, you know?
And I can list a million of those situations.
I lost my shit in that moment.
Just the fact that that is possible.
Here's another thing.
I was playing around with glowing lance.
And I had a speed up on it.
And I realized that it could cut through material.
And I had trouble because I couldn't dig through things, right?
And for the longest time, I didn't know what to do.
So I started hitting people through walls and shit.
And that was so fun.
And then I realized, holy shit, I can make a small hole with my glowing lance and teleport through it with my teleport wand.
When I realized that, I felt so fucking smart.
God damn, that was cool.
One of the best things ever.
And just today, I don't know if you saw that part, but I was trying to dig up again through the holy mountains and backtrack.
But I didn't really have a digging wand, but I did have an earthquake thing.
So I would earthquake everything and then dig away the falling debris.
Pretty much playing Space Invaders.
The fact that you could just do that shit.
And I get the feeling sometimes that, man, I'm not sure anyone else has done this.
You know, but probably they have.
It's an old game by now, I guess.
So maybe I'm not the first to try that.
But just the feeling you get of, man, this may actually be something novel, you know?
Feels amazing.
Yeah.
Oh yeah, the first time I fired a homing rock in the holy mountain.
I got so fucking scared.
It's the same kind of energy as that wild propane tank just flying about, you know?
It's the chaos of it and the fear that it may hit you in the face.
And it just looks so violent.
It was so cool.
Hey Raiko, there's a ton of stuff in this game that is probably impossible to discover without the wiki.
What do you want to do about that?
Nothing.
I'm prepared to not know everything about this game and that's fine.
I'm gonna stop playing this game when I don't have fun with it anymore or I get tired of it.
Sometimes you just need breaks from games.
But I'm okay with never finding all the secrets.
That's totally okay with me.
I will find as much as I can on my own, have fun with it as long as I can and then I'll play something else.
And maybe in the future when I get that itch again because man, the neuter itch is real.
That first homing rock was even better than your last one.
It had accelerated homing, did it?
Damn.
I'm so sad I didn't use it.
I was too afraid it would hit me in the face.
I mean, it's not a bad thing to assume, right?
Falling debris usually hurts you.
You have 1500 hours and you still occasionally learn new tricks.
That's wild.
How many wins do you have?
I'm just curious.
Not that it's a competition or anything.
Are you going for a lot of wins or are you going for just exploring the world?
Addy is Maddie.
Hey, started playing neuter but feel I'm getting killed immediately.
I know that feeling, man.
It happens.
My best advice is to just go slowly.
Just go slowly, one enemy at a time.
Try to understand what's happening.
That's how I started.
And it worked out pretty well.
But I also died a lot.
Just have fun with it.
I started playing when Oliver started.
Today I discovered something about Luminous Drills.
That's awesome, I lied.
I'm actually so happy that other people are trying the games that I'm playing.
Like, I just recently started Prey.
And I see so many comments saying that they also started playing it because it looked cool and they didn't know about it.
That's the coolest feeling, you know?
We're all experiencing the games together, sort of.
At least those that start with me.
Getting noiset is inevitable.
Noiset.
I love that.
When you start playing, the question is not whether you die, but whether you learn something new from it.
Exactly.
See, I'm more happy about my death just before than dying to the last boss, you know?
Because I learned something new in that area with the big pool of water and the hut.
And the alchemist note and all that stuff.
And the portals down below.
Man, there are so many secrets, it seems, you know?
It's going to be really interesting to try and figure out.
But I'm also prepared never to figure it out.
Pretty much every game I play...
You start playing it, too.
Nice.
We can play it together.
For Prey, though, I've always wanted to play it, but now I have to in order to avoid spoilers.
Yeah, that's the thing.
You definitely want to avoid spoilers with Prey.
Let me just say that.
I mean, most games, I guess.
But that one in particular.
Death in the pursuit of knowledge is the highest form of sacrifice to the gods.
I like that, Yuduri.
Very poetic of you.
Anyway, guys, I need to eat some food because I'm starving.
And yeah, I'm just going to cut the...
Like, slap off the band-aid.
That doesn't make sense in English.
I can't speak English.
I will see you next time.
Thanks for watching.
Let's raid someone who's streaming Noita.
I'm going to do that real quick.
Let's see who's here.
I'm going to put on same category.
How about...
There's a guy called...
Let's see here.
Certified Psycho.
Feeling extra slimy today.
Let's hand it over to him.
Torpor Naut.
Let's raid Torpor Naut.
Such a cool feature.
You can do this on Twitch.
All right.
I will see you guys in the next stream.
Thank you for watching.
Have a good day.
Bye-bye.